Hello

I'm Lexie Crawford

Full Stack Developer (MERN) - Masters of Arts in Teaching EASLEY, SC 29642 (864) 3631977

lexcraw4d@gmail.com

Github - Github Profile and Repositories

https://github.com/lexcraw4d

Portfolio-Personal Portfolio

https://lexcraw4d.github.io/

LinkedIn - https://www.linkedin.com/in/alexiacrawford/

Skills

Github, Git (Version Control), HTML/CSS. JavaScript, Node.js, Express, RESTful APIs, Third Party APIs, jQuery, Bootstrap. Object Oriented Programming MySQL/NoSQL, Relational Databases, ORM, ODM, Heroku, React. Jest, Test Driven Data, RESTful APIs, GraphQL, Web Security and Session Storage. User Authentication, Conflict Resolution, Critical Thinking. Desire for students to succeed. Coaching. Teamwork. Teaching. Building communities. Organization. Leadership, Networking. Advocating for others. Collaborating with students, colleagues, administration, Effective verbal and written communication, Schedule and conferencing. Student records. Academic Support, FERPA

Projects

Helping Hands: https://helping-hands-deux.herokuapp.com/

 $\textbf{Summary:} \ \textbf{Helping Hands seeks to serve the less fortunate through grass roots efforts of engaged community members.$

Role: Backend Designer

Tools: Node.js, Express, NoSQL, Mogoose, JWT Authentication, MongoDB, GraphQL

Local Heroes: https://localheroes21.herokuapp.com/

Summary: Local Heroes is a web application to assist travelers and enhance their traveling experience by connection them with local

individuals that have similar interests.

Role: Backend Designer

Tools: Node.js, Express, MySQL, Sequelize, JWT Authentication, Handlebars

Budget Tracker: https://intense-brushlands-65502.herokuapp.com/

Summary: Application to keep track of an individual's spendings and earnings.

Role: Implement Progressive Web Application Architecture Tools: Node, Express, MongoDB, Mongoose, Service Workers

Weather Dashboard: https://lexcraw4d.github.io/Weather/

Summary: Application that provides weather based on input location.

Role: Create a full stack website using third party APIs.

Tools: Node, Third Party APIs, Bootstrap, Vanilla JavaScript, HTML, CSS

Previous Experience

Trilogy Education (Full Stack Boot Camp), New York, NY — Teacher Assistant/Learning Assistant (Part-Time)

August 2021 - PRESENT

- Claim and respond to student questions via virtual platform and respond within 15-20 minutes
- Solve for and respond to technical, conceptual, and general curriculum-based challenges
- Articulate clear and thorough responses that support student's needs
- Support the Instructor during lectures and educational product management activities
- Answer students' questions during class sessions
- Utilize Zoom's "breakout-rooms" feature during activities and in-class projects to assist the students, as needed
- Assist the Instructor with distributing class materials
- Ensure that homework is graded on-time, and occasionally assist with grading
- Lead weekly office hours on one weekend day for 2 hours

Blackboard, Greenville, SC — *Enrollment Specialist* February 2020 - PRESENT

- Communicated effectively via phone, email, and text with prospective and current students.
- Advise students on current & future educational goals.
- Ensures all mandatory prerequisites and admission requirements are met.
- Counsel students on personal issues conflicting with academics.
- Assist students with onboarding and tracking progress towards their goals.
- Established and maintained positive professional relationships with students.
- Collaborated with faculty and administration to ensure the best interests of students.

Legacy Early College, Greenville, SC — Elementary Teacher and Grade Level Chair

January 2016 - 2020

- Lead grade level meetings centered on best instructional strategies and practices to meet the needs of all students..
- . Prepared materials for lessons, assignments and assessments and evaluated, corrected and graded student performance to identify gaps in skills or knowledge and set realistic goals.
- Helped students develop self-esteem and life skills by fostering positive relationships.
- Fostered a positive classroom environment encouraging and promoting student growth while developing an excellent rapport with them.
- Record scores schoolwide.

CVS Pharmacy, Greenville, SC — Lead District Pharmacy Technician (CPhT)

2010 - 2016

- Recruited, trained and guided 13 stores for Pharmacy Technician Roles which improved overall performance.
- -. Counted, measured, and compounded medications following standard procedures.
- Provided consultations and answered inquiries from patients, healthcare professionals and physicians regarding drugs, potential side effects and specified use.
- Communicated with prescribers to verify medication dosages, refill authorizations and patient information.
- Consulted with insurance company representatives to complete claims processing, resolve concerns and reconcile payments..

Education

University of Texas, Austin, TX — Full Stack Certification 2021

Liberty University, Lynchburg, VA — Masters of Arts in Teaching 2017-2019

University of South Carolina, Aiken, SC — B.S. Business Administration and Management 2012-2016

 $\textbf{Greenville Technical College,} Greenville, SC-Associate of Science, Pharmacy Technician {\tt 2010-2012} \\$

Awards

Lion Paw Award 2017 - Teacher of the Quarter, Dean's List (multiple terms). Third Grade Mathematics Team Lead, Phi Theta Kappa Honor Society, National and State Certification Pharmacy Technician

Volunteer/Intern

Project RX, Susan G. Komen Campaign, Backend Internship with Gambix LLC